本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 小白 JoJo 饭团 狐狸锁骨 Dennings Floralin
校对： 小妖怪   后期： Pilar
彼岸是天堂 第二季 第五集
"美食厅"
说实话 达德利先生 我什么时候迟到过?
Be honest, Mr Dudley, when have you ever known me to be late?
我不是在查你的岗 山姆 是我的表
It's not you I'm checking on, Sam. It's me watch.
好像停了
Seems to have stopped.
那就买个新的 先生
Get yourself a new one, sir.
这块表跟了我很多年了 我要拿去修修
I've had this watch many years. I'll have it mended.
我要是你 先生 我会配备一块璀璨的怀表
If I were you, sir, I'd want to be standing there
每一秒都走得如你一般稳当
with a shiny new timepiece, every little tick as reliable as you are.
也许我们该让你去推销怀表
Perhaps we should let you loose on a promotion for pocket watches.
无上光荣 先生
That would be an honour and a privilege, sir.
噢 有奖金么?
Oh, would there be a bonus in it?
你怎么看? 梅尔托
What do you make of it, Myrtle?
我怎么看? 先生?
What do I make of it, sir?
这是个值得纪念的时刻
A moment to cherish.
我们华丽的美食厅的第一天
The first day of our splendid new Food Hall.
走过托尔盖特街的顾客们将与这些
Customers who come along Tollgate Street will be met
珍馐佳肴见面
by all manner of culinary delights.
你是指食物么 先生?
Do you mean food, sir?
这栋楼荒弃了一年多
This building has stood derelict for a year and more,
它象征着犹豫和失败
a mark of hesitation and failure.
现在它象征着一种决心
Now it stands as a declaration of intent,
宣告汤姆・威斯顿将一手把天堂百货
an assertion that Tom Weston means to raise The Paradise
捧上新的高度
to new heights.
真好 你满意我也开心 威斯顿先生
Well, I'm pleased that you're so pleased, Mr Weston, sir.
你怎么没去工作 梅尔托?
Why aren't you at work, Myrtle?
我做了
I was.
我 我是说 我就做
I-I mean, I will be.
我在工作
I am.
我就是被你的慷慨陈词震住了 先生
I just got caught up in all your declarations, sir.
分享佣金?
Share our commission?
是的 每周结束我们大家将把佣金平分
At the end of every week we will divide the total amongst all of the girls, yes.
为什么我们得这样? 这对那些勤勤恳恳
Why would we do that? Those of us who work hardest,
战战兢兢伺候老主顾的人不公平
who take a care to pamper our regular customers,
你这是把我们应得的给夺走了
you'd be taking the earnings out of our purses.
但要是我们把佣金集中在一起
But if we pool the money,
当我们中一人得病或者遭了祸事
if one of us is sick or has a run of bad luck,
就相当有了保障
then there's a safety net.
要是我们有为彼此工作的概念
If we feel that we're working for each other,
相信我们会挣得更多
then I believe we'll earn more.
非得这样么?
Do we have to?
可是苏西 你挣得最少
But Susy, you earn the least commission of all.
即使是一星半点也是我挣的
It might be nothing but it is my nothing.
难道不是竞争 戒备和恐惧
Isn't the competition, the jealousy and fear,
鞭策着我们努力工作的么?
isn't that what spurs us on?
我觉得不是非要竞争不可 我们都爱这份工作
I don't believe we have to compete. We all love our work.
- 我建议投票表决 - 投票?
- I suggest we have a vote. - A vote?
要是你输了呢? 那你不就威严扫地了?
What if you lose? Won't that undermine your authority?
我不这么看 克莱拉
I don't see it that way, Clara.
如果是妙计 总会赢得支持的
If it's a good idea, it will win.
如果不是 就不会
If it's not, then it won't.
同意分享佣金的人 请举手
Raise your hand, please, if you think we should share the commission.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是达德利的想法
It was Dudley's suggestion.
我们把柜台安置在醒目位置
We've placed the counter prominently
陈列着精美时钟吸引眼球
and stationed decorative clocks to draw the eye.
剩下的就靠山姆的三寸不烂之舌了
The rest is in Sam's capable hands.
关键是 让绅士们感觉没有一块怀表揣着
The point is, is to make the gentlemen feel behind the times
就落伍了
without a little ticker in their pocket.
这不在于他们能否买的起怀表
It's not whether they can afford it,
而是他们能否经得住过时的恐惧感
it's whether they can afford to live of being in fear of being late.
珠光宝气 就和我看到美食厅的感觉一样
Jewellery. Just as I have opened the Food Hall,
你的特色明显是珠宝展
you feature a prominent display of jewellery.
这不是装饰品 威斯顿先生
These are not ornaments, Mr Weston.
它们是实用的东西 功能性的工具
They are practical pieces, functional instruments.
以金银包裹 珠宝点缀的功能性工具
Functional instruments of gold and silver, decorated with jewels.
请允许我说一句
If I may,
先生 我们需要的是能让顾客神魂颠倒的东西
what we need, gentlemen, is something to fascinate the customers.
也许是一块让人叹为观止的怀表
Perhaps, one watch for them to marvel at,
一种奢华夺目的美 使人为之驻足
something truly extravagant, so they will dwell long enough
久到足够我施展浑身解数
for me to work my magic on them.
- 克莱拉? - 嗯?
- Clara? - Mmm?
我一直在想你为何会投票赞成分享佣金
I can't help wondering why you voted to share the commission.
我不傻
I'm no fool.
举手反对你 我就会输
Put me hand up against you, I'd have lost
然后独我一个像是挑衅生事
and be left looking like a trouble-maker.
- 我相信这不是你的理由 - 那你说呢?
- I don't believe that was your reason. - Then what was it?
其他人都不喜欢这个提议
The other girls didn't like the notion
你又不想我孤立无援的
and you didn't want to leave me stranded.
你觉得我是和事佬? 你还是不懂我 德妮丝
Think I have a heart of soap? You still don't know me, Denise.
那就是你明白这是个妙计
Then you know it's a good idea.
想听真话么?
Do you want the truth?
你让我们来投票 我感激不尽
You asked us to vote. I was grateful for that.
很好 因为我们将有下一次投票了
Good. Because we're going to have another vote.
- 苍天啊 这次又是什么? - 不知道
- Oh, Lord! What about this time? - I don't know.
我想让每个人轮流提个建议
I'd like each of the girls in turn to make a proposal
然后我们投票表决
and we'll vote on it.
如果你第一个提出 我将不胜感激 克莱拉
I would appreciate if you would go first, Clara.
如果你看见一个男人戴着一块精美的表
If you watch a man with a fine watch,
你怎么看?
what do you see?
他是个与时间同行的人
He is a man with time on his side.
一个不用依靠时钟的人
A man who won't be watching the clock.
时间不等人
Time waits for no man.
我们每周一起去游一次泳 算是女孩出游节
Once a week we go swimming together. A girl's day out.
我们可以看着苏西沉底然后哈哈大笑
We can all watch Susy sinking and have a laugh.
如果新开的美食厅反响不错 先生
If the new Food Hall is a success, sir,
威斯顿扩张的胃口会增大
Mr Weston will have a taste for more expansion.
他已经和我说了很多
He's already said as much to me.
难不成要眼睁睁地等到难...难以企及?
Are we to wait until he is b...beyond reach?
我们得给他们施压了
We must put more pressure on them.
我们需要做的是让威斯顿先生
What we need, sir, is for Mr Weston to feel
感到在这儿就是丢人现眼
that being here is a humiliation to him.
如果他察觉出自己的妻子还喜欢你...
If he senses that his wife still favours you...
要我做这个 鸡皮疙瘩掉一地了
It makes my skin crawl to do this.
威斯顿太太享受特权带来的好处 不是么?
Mrs Weston enjoys all the benefits of privilege, does she not?
你我点点滴滴日积月累到到今日
You and I have carved our lives from nothing.
先生 这个女人夺走了你苦心经营的天堂百货
Sir. The same woman stripped you of everything you had worked for.
同样是这个女人寸步不让
The same woman did not flinch,
把你从这个城镇赶走
driving you from this town.
请你思考一下 她为何召你回来?
I ask you to consider - why does she summon you back here?
你以为她会对你心存善意?
Do you think she is brimming with good intentions towards you?
- 不 - 我们时间紧迫了
- No. - We have a limited time to act.
你的思想必须集中在必须得到的东西上
You must focus your mind only on what must be achieved.
我们需要别的什么 我们需要更多
We need something else. Something more.
某种能够干扰汤姆・威斯顿的力量
Something to cut into Tom Weston.
你有主意了 先生?
You have an idea in mind, sir?
也许
Perhaps.
是什么?
What is it?
我还是不说的好
I'd rather not say.
没有犹豫的功夫了
There is no room for hesitation.
你必须去追求她 莫里
You must go after her, Moray,
施展你的美男计
with all those charms you're famous for.
我觉得这事我需要询问你的丈夫
I realise that this is something I need to ask your husband about,
但是我认为需要先征求你的允许
but I felt obliged to seek your permission first
因为这是很私人的事情 寄托着你的感情
since it's such a personal matter, such a tender issue to you.
什么这么敏感?
What could be so sensitive?
你父亲的怀表
Your father's watch.
我没法控制地想
I can't shake off the idea that
这块怀表会成为一场展览最神奇的重头戏
it would make the most magical centrepiece for a display...
我父亲的怀表?
My father's watch?
对 对 它那么的精美绝伦 会吸引...
Yes, yes, it's such a thing of beauty that it would draw...
它对我的意义无法估量
It is precious to me beyond reckoning.
你认为 为了吸引贩夫走卒进你的商场
Do you suppose I would dangle it before any passing drayman
我会由它悬挂在他们面前摇摆?
in the hope that he will come into your store?
我无意冒犯 凯瑟琳
I had no wish to cause offence, Katherine.
可是你却口不择言
And you made no effort to exercise consideration.
我庆幸没有去问你的丈夫...
I'm glad that I did not ask your husband...
表不在汤姆手上
Tom does not have it.
不好意思 我还以为 呃...
I'm sorry. I simply thought that, erm...
我记得你父亲说 由于他膝下无子
I remember your father saying since he had no sons,
他会把怀表传给你的丈夫
he would leave it to the man you married.
是的 这个
Yes. Well.
那是他曾经考虑过的事情
That may have been something he considered at one time.
呃 希望你能原谅我的不善言辞 凯瑟琳
Erm... I hope you can forgive my clumsiness, Katherine,
但是 我想要用这场展览来表示尊重...
but I intended for the display to show respect...
如果你称呼我为威斯顿夫人 我将不胜感激
I would appreciate it if you would address me as Mrs Weston.
当然 威斯顿夫人
Of course. Mrs Weston.
当然
Of course.
德妮丝 请进
Denise. Come in.
你想要和我谈谈是么 威斯顿先生?
You wanted to speak with me, Mr Weston, sir?
从你成为女装部主管开始
Since you've become Head of Ladieswear there is a matter
我越来越关心一个问题
that is of growing concern to me.
很抱歉 先生
I'm sorry to hear that, sir.
似乎你引进了更多现代化
It seems you're introducing more modern,
或者可以称之为民主的管理方法
one might even call them democratic methods.
- 先生 我只是... - 大开眼界
- Sir, I only want... - Most impressive.
我关心的是为何其他的部门还不跟上
My concern is why the other departments so patently lag behind.
我想把所有部门的主管召集起来 听你演讲
I intend to gather all the heads of department together so that you might address them.
也许你可以用你的魔力去鼓舞他们
Perhaps you can infuse them with a touch of your magic.
先生 我不确定我能...
Sir, I am not sure that it is my...
怎么 你不喜欢这主意? 哪还能有更好的?
What, you don't like the idea? What could be better?
我将得益于你的青春奔放
I will gain the benefit of your youthful ebullience
你也将享受你应得的赞誉
and you will enjoy the recognition you deserve.
真的 德妮丝 你可以让自己稍稍享受一下
Surely, Denise, you can let yourself bask just a little
同事们的钦羡
in the admiration of your peers?
- 那 我... - 很好
- Well, I... - Good.
我来安排
I will make the arrangements.
我受邀向各部门主管介绍
I have been asked to make a presentation to the heads of department
我们经营女装部的经验
about how we do things in Ladieswear.
莫里先生为什么让你做这种事?
Why would Mr Moray want you to do a thing like that?
不是莫里叫的 是威斯顿先生
It was not Moray who asked, it was Mr Weston.
我觉得我们可以一起完成 给他们看
What I thought was, we could do it together - show them.
我们需要投票吗? 我要投票 我要投赞成票
Do we have to vote on it? I'll vote. I'll vote yes.
我从没出过风头
I never get to show off.
这可不是出风头 苏西
It's not about showing off, Susy.
而是陈述
It's a presentment.
克莱拉?
Clara?
威斯顿先生为什么让你做这个?
Why would Mr Weston ask you to do such a thing?
他说他想引进现代的工作方法
He said he wants to introduce modern ways of working.
那就是了 莫里先生怎么看?
Oh, that must be it, then. What does Mr Moray think about this?
我还没告诉他
I haven't told him yet.
看来要招人议论了
Cat. Pigeons.
年轻姑娘们都一样
All young girls are the same.
十岁的时候 想变成十一岁
When we are ten, we want to be eleven,
十一岁的时候 想变成十二岁
when we are eleven, we want to be twelve.
我坚持认为 应该享受当下的年龄 芙罗拉
I insist you delight in the age that you are, Flora.
我今天对德妮丝说了完全一样的话
I was saying quite the same thing to Denise today.
德妮丝?
Denise?
年轻是她能胜任商场的工作的决定性优势
Her youth is her defining asset in her role in the store.
充满热情
All that enthusiasm.
别人几乎无法限制她
One can hardly put a cap on it.
我已经决定了 要激发她全部的热情
I've determined to make the most of it.
你准备怎么做呢 亲爱的?
And how will you do that, darling?
我要让她成为榜样
I will let her serve as an example
让别人知道该如何处理自己的工作
to others of how to do their jobs.
她真是个人物
She's quite something.
你一定会迷倒并教育我们每一个人 德妮丝
I'm sure you will no doubt charm and educate every one of us, Denise.
我只是来分享一些
All I will do is share a few things I have tried
似乎能使我们的工作更容易的经验
which seem to make our work easier.
我只希望资深的员工不会觉得
I only hope the more senior members of staff don't see you
你自认为比他们高明
as placing yourself above them.
但今天对你而言 一定特别美好 当然了
But it will be a wonderful day for you, of course.
同事们不会讨厌德妮丝 我们非常了解她
Her colleagues won't think badly of Denise. We know her enough.
我们都知道 她只是希望百货公司能更好
We all realise that she only wishes to be of benefit to the store.
我相信 她会持友谊精神完成
I'm sure it will be done in the spirit of companionship.
我也会对她介绍的方法感兴趣
I for one will be interested in what methods she has introduced.
威斯顿先生不持任何怀疑
Mr Weston would not countenance any doubts.
他已经认可了吗?
You've already accepted?
没错 我... 他问过我...
Yes. I... He asked me and...
那你一定得充分利用这次机会了
Then you must make the most of the occasion.
威斯顿夫人
Mrs Weston.
我改变主意了 这是我父亲的手表
I have had a change of heart. My father's watch.
我现在相信了
I appreciate now that
你把它放在橱窗展示 是表示对我父亲的尊重
your intention is to honour my father by putting it on display.
我没有理由拒绝你的请求
I see no good reason not to concede to your wishes.
我非常感激
Then I am most grateful.
山姆?
Sam?
山姆 看来你的重头展品出现了
Sam, it seems we have your centrepiece for you.
它有上百年的年头了 是我父亲的继承财产
It is over a hundred years old. My father inherited it.
老实说 虽然我经常对顾客编故事
To be honest, as much as I cook up a tale for the customers,
但我一直认为手表不过就是手表
I always thought a watch was just a watch.
我知道我要的是神奇的东西 先生
I know I asked for something magical, sir,
但这宝贝 我必须得让他们排队看看
but that'll have them queuing up just to take a look at it.
我父亲用这个教我看时间
My father taught me to read the time with this.
那是每天最精彩的时刻
It was the high point of every day.
它让我着了魔了
It has me bewitched.
你让我想起了自己小时候 山姆
You remind me of when I was a child, Sam.
我也曾用过完全相同的词 它让我着了魔了
I used the self-same words about it. It had me bewitched.
我父亲过去常常用它催眠我
My father used to hypnotise me with it.
他在我眼前轻轻地摇晃这只手表
He would swing it gently before my eyes
轻声说话 让我相信他把我带入了幻境
and speak softly and convince me he had induced a trance over me.
它是个奇迹 我应该珍惜它
It is little wonder that I should treasure it so.
我们会像你一样珍惜它的 夫人
We will treasure it just as much, ma'am.
有件事 我希望你能考虑考虑 莫里
There is one aspect of this matter for which I would ask your consideration, Moray.
我父亲希望把那只手表传给我的丈夫
My father's wishes - that the watch be passed on to the man I marry.
汤姆不知道
Tom does not know.
如果你能保密 我将感激不尽
I would appreciate it if you made no mention.
是 是 当然了 还轮不到我来告诉他
Why, yes, yes, of course. It's not my place to tell him.
我意识到您对它的依恋 威斯顿夫人
I realise how deeply attached you are to it, Mrs Weston.
请叫我凯瑟琳
Please, call me Katherine.
我从没见过这么惊人的东西
I never laid my eyes on anything quite so marvellous.
你觉得它值多少钱 达德利先生?
How much do you suppose it's worth, Mr Dudley?
值我们俩下半辈子的工资 山姆
It would keep the two of us in wages for the rest of our lives, Sam.
但是 你能感觉到
Aye, but you get the feeling that this is worth more
它比钱更值钱
than pounds, shillings and pence.
我希望你没有再次干预莫里的事 乔纳斯
I hope you are not meddling in Moray's affairs again, Jonas.
就如你所见 达德利先生
As you can see, Mr Dudley,
我只是在处理自己的事
I'm simply going about my duties.
就是我看不到的才让我担心
It is what I cannot see that concerns me.
我看见莫里和威斯顿夫人在一起
I have watched Moray with Mrs Weston.
他为什么对她这么热忱 这么亲密?
Why is he so cordial, so intimate with her?
发生什么事了?
What is going on?
先生 我不能代表莫里先生
I cannot speak on Mr Moray's behalf, sir.
你说得越礼貌 就越是在狡猾地逃避我的问题
The more polite your tongue, the more slippery you are at avoiding my questions.
我无意冒犯
I mean no offence.
你也无意开诚布公 跟我说实话
Yet you have no wish to be open and honest with me, either.
我知道是你在操纵他
I know that it is you leading him down this path
因为你们俩一个字也不说
and since I can prise no information from either of you,
我得说 你以为你最清楚吗?
I will say this. Do you suppose you know best?
我希望你考虑一下现状 先生
I ask you to consider the circumstances, sir.
谁拥有天堂百货 你看到了正义存在吗?
Who owns The Paradise? Is there justice in what you see?
如果汤姆・威斯顿掌握权力
Do you believe life will get easier
你觉得我们任何人的生活能更好过吗?
for any of us while Tom Weston holds the whip?
尤其是莫里先生
Especially for Mr Moray.
你能感觉到自己在看它吗?
Can you feel your eyes drawn to it?
好似你的视线无法从它身上移开?
Like you can't stop looking at it?
当然 这还不是它的美妙之处
That's not the beauty of it, of course.
虽然它的确是个漂亮的家伙!
Well, it is a handsome thing!
但这里面的东西 是无法解释的力量
But what we have here is a power beyond explanation.
让我宁愿为它万死不辞
May I fall down and die.
难道没觉得仿佛时间都静止了吗?
Does it not feel as though time itself has stopped?
你有手表吗 先生?
Do you own a watch, sir?
你看起来很了解时间的重要性
You look like a man who knows the importance of time,
谁不希望自己的口袋里有一块古老的锡铁表呢
who wouldn't have any old piece of tin in your pocket.
我是说对了 还是说对了?
Am I right or am I right?
这个手表 不在于是否有人买得起它
This watch here, it's not a matter of whether a fella can afford it.
而在于是否有人买得起 而不想拥有它
It's whether a fella can afford not to own it.
如果我们需要决定一件事情 我们就投票
If there's an issue we need to decide upon, we vote on it.
我本来不想分红
I didn't want to share my bonus
但要投票决定时 我就同意了
but when it was voted in, then I did.
我觉得我现在工作更努力了
I think I work harder now
因为如果姑娘们在为我工作
because if the girls are earning commission for me,
我也应该为她们工作
I ought to make commission for them, too.
我们甚至投票决定今天是否来这里做这个介绍
We even had a vote about whether we would talk to you all today.
作为销售员 我感觉自己是团队一员时
As a shop girl, I did my best work when I felt involved,
工作效率最高
part of a team.
我觉得 如果我们都很享受
I think if we all enjoy ourselves,
顾客也会愿意来这里
then customers will enjoy coming here.
以上就是全部 谢谢大家
I think that's everything. Thank you for coming today.
也许我们应该投票决定是否应该结束
Perhaps we should have a vote to see if our little presentation's over.
非常好!
Splendid!
今天 德妮丝小姐和她的姑娘们的展示
What Miss Denise and her girls have illustrated for us today
说明我们绝不能固步自封
is that we must not rest on our laurels.
过去的成功秘诀不一定适用于今天
What has brought success in the past will not do today.
很清楚 我们最好意识到
Clearly, we would do well to see
今天介绍的方法是前进的方向
that today's presentation leads the way.
她不令人敬畏吗 莫里?
Is she not formidable, Moray?
她们都令人敬畏 先生 她们都令人敬畏
They all were, sir. They all were.
大家都对我非常好
Everybody was so kind to me.
他们都来问我问题 来祝贺我
They were full of questions and congratulations.
你觉得如何 亲爱的?
What did you think, sweetheart?
告诉我 老实说
Tell me. Tell me honestly.
我只在乎你的看法
Your opinion's the only one that matters.
我...
I...
我很高兴你为这里带来了活力 德妮丝
I delight in seeing you light up this place, Denise,
但是我们不能忘记 事情不该是这样
but we must not forget, it is not meant to be this way.
我们不应该在他们的怜悯或者帮助下生活
We are not meant to be under their mercy or favour.
这里应该属于我们 你知道吗?
This place should be ours. Do you see?
当然了
Of course.
有时候我会激动得忘乎所以
Sometimes I get carried away.
我必须尽全力
I must do my best.
这就是我们必须竭尽全力
That is why we must go to any lengths
让我重新拥有天堂百货的原因
to make The Paradise mine again.
而你就是我的女主角
And then you will be my leading lady.
我今天简直就是台推销机器 艾德蒙
I was a selling machine today, Edmund.
我真希望你能看到我们今天的表现
I wish you could have seen us.
你一直都表现得像是一台推销机器 山姆
You're always a selling machine, Sam.
所有人都有一技之长
Every man has to be good at one thing.
我拼命兜售 就好像今天是世界末日一样!
I was peddling like it was the end of the world!
你想知道为什么吗?
And you want to know why?
我的幸运物
My lucky charm.
它怎么在你的口袋里? 这东西可值一大笔钱
What are you doing with that in your pocket? It's worth a fortune.
我就想揣上几个小时
I thought, for a few hours,
商店已经关门了 没有人会注意到
while the shop's closed, no-one will notice.
想感受一下怀揣宝物的感觉
See what it feels like to have something precious in my pocket.
实话告诉你 感觉棒极了
And to be honest, it feels marvellous.
这可不像你 山姆 招惹是非
It's not like you, Sam, to flirt with trouble.
我知道 我在陈列室的原位上铺了一块黑布
I know. I put a black cloth over the spot in the cabinet.
没人会注意到它不见了的
No-one will even notice it's missing.
但如果你不小心摔了它或者弄丢了怎么办?
But what if you drop it or you lose it?
我看到它躺在那里 光彩夺目
I saw it there, spellbinding,
我难以自持
I couldn't resist it.
它的质感 它的设计理念
The feel of it. The idea of it.
你得承认 艾德蒙
You have to admit, Edmund,
这是个尤物 有生命的瑰宝
it's a thing of beauty, a living wonder.
这确实很美
It's certainly splendid
即时这样我也不认为你应该把它拿出来
but I wouldn't thank you for having that in my pocket.
只是这样握着它
Just by having it here,
我就觉得我似乎又高大了一点
I feel an inch taller,
更英俊潇洒 更无所畏惧了
more handsome, more fearless.
世界之王
King of the world.
这种感觉有一个名字 那就是诱惑
There's a name for that. It's called temptation.
你应该抵制诱惑
The thing is to resist it.
啊 你已经老了 就是这样 畏手畏脚的了!
Ah, you're old, that's all. Lost your daring, man!
快点 问我几点了
Ask me what time it is.
- 几点了? - 山姆的时间 没错
- What time is it? - Sam's time, that's what.
是山姆扬眉吐气的时间
Sam's time to be on top.
他在耍我
He is toying with me.
他知道如果他把那些赞美和成就
He knows that if he can heap praise and advancement
加于德妮丝身上
onto Denise that
我会感到煎熬
it will torment me.
那么您要做出选择 先生
Then you have a choice, sir.
要么让他占上风
You can let him win the day,
要么你可以表现出同样的老道和勇敢
or you can meet him with as much
与他正面交锋
cunning and daring.
如果您能成功地让威斯顿先生清楚地意识到
If you manage to plant into Mr Weston's mind
他的妻子在对您献殷勤的话
the clear idea that his wife is pursuing you,
他会想找个人聊一聊的
he will want someone to talk to.
我已经和他建立起了些许的信任
I have already established some trust between he and I.
要是我让他发现我对您抱有怨言的话
If I let him see that I hold a festering resentment towards you,
他会对我更加信赖
he might begin to confide in me.
怎么了 乔纳斯?
What is it, Jonas?
哦 请原谅我 先生
Oh, forgive me, sir.
我不应该表现出这样沮丧的状态
I should not let my frustration show in such a manner.
恕我冒昧 让我回去工作吧
If I may, I will return to my duties.
你因为什么事情不开心吗?
Something has upset you?
感谢您的关心 先生
I appreciate your concern, sir,
但是我不能用我的对上司不满的情绪来麻烦您
but I cannot trouble you with my grievances against my employer.
我这样的行为真是太可悲了 恕我冒昧...
It was petty of me to behave in this way. If I may...
莫里? 他做了什么让你这样不安?
Moray? What has he done to disturb you?
这些年来 我尽职尽责的服侍这个男人
I have served that man for some years with loyalty and dedication
十分恪尽职守
beyond the call of duty.
难道我不值得得到雇主的信任吗?
Do I not deserve the reward of my employer's trust?
不知为什么我觉得信任感对我非常重要 先生
I don't know why it matters so much to me to be trusted, sir,
但是确实非常重要
but it does.
在我看来 你想错了方向 乔纳斯
It seems to me you have the equation the wrong way around, Jonas.
你应该扪心自问 莫里是否真的值得你的忠诚
You should ask yourself if Moray is worthy of your loyalty.
她亲自告诉我的... 凯瑟琳・威斯顿
She told me herself... Katherine Weston.
那块表具有魔力
That watch has powers.
催眠的魔力
Hypnotic powers.
她的家族里 过去的时候
Her family, in her family, going back,
他们会用表来催眠对方
they used to mesmerise each other with it.
她的父亲精通于此
Her father was the master of it.
要不然你想他是如何得到财富的
How else do you suppose he got his riches?
魔力 不可思议的魔力
Powers. Incredible powers.
把你那套说辞留给顾客们吧 山姆
Save your patter for the customers, Sam.
我站在这儿
As I stand here.
好吧 坐在这儿 我自己可以感觉到
Well, sit here. I felt it myself.
我相信他 什么是催眠的 山姆?
I believe him. What is hypnotic, Sam?
是催眠 苏西 就是一种睡眠
Hypnosis, Susy, well, it's a kind of sleep.
好吧 也不完全是睡觉 就好像...
Well, not sleep exactly. It's like...
啊 和入睡的状态不同
Ah, it's not like being asleep.
就好像你在这儿但其实不在这儿
It's like being here but not being here.
苏西即使是在最佳状态的时候也是这种感觉
That's what Susy feels like at the best of times.
就好像是眩晕 那种感觉
It's like being dazzled, kind of thing.
什么 像喝醉了一样吗?
What, like being drunk?
你怎么知道喝醉了是什么感觉?
What do you know about being drunk?
不是 催眠 就是...
No. Hypnosis, it's...
被催眠了就好像是处在一个无所不能的世界里
Being hypnotised is like being in a world where everything is possible.
如果你想跳舞 就可以像芭蕾舞者翩然起舞
If you want to dance you'll be like a ballerina.
要是你想唱歌 你的歌喉会像鸣鸟一样悦耳
If you want to sing, you'll warble like a songbird.
你好像是活在你的愿望里
It's like being in a kind of wish.
那我们所有人都应该一直被催眠啊
We should all do it all the time.
哦 我想被催眠的
Oh, I want to be hypnotic.
是被催眠
Hypnotised.
你会催眠吗? 能不能把我催眠 山姆?
Can you? Can you hypnotise me, Sam?
小心点 苏西 他会把你弄昏之后
Careful, Susy, he'll put you under
告诉你把你每周的薪水交给他
then tell you to give him your wages every week.
要是你想体验一把灵魂出窍的感觉
If you are looking for an out of body experience,
那你可找对人啦 苏西
you have come to the right fella, Susy.
今夜 商店打烊后
Tonight. After we close.
- 我们都能来吗? - 为什么不呢?
- Can we all come? - Why not?
来吧 在大堂 我们打烊之后
Go on, then. In the Great Hall. After we close.
我想说做的好 梅尔托
I wanted to say well done, Myrtle.
对我说 先生?
To me, sir?
那些你为了新的美食厅制作的面包
The breads, pies, pastries you've cooked for
馅饼 糕点 让人口水直流啊
the new Food Hall are mouth-watering.
- 销售额非常不错 - 真的吗 先生?
- The sales are extraordinary. - Are they, sir?
- 我是说 谢谢您 先生 - 是的
I mean, thank you, sir. Oh, yes.
现在我们必须更进一步
Now we must step up the splendour.
你的厨房做出点特别的东西
Perhaps something special from your kitchen
让美食厅成为天堂百货的谈资
to make the Food Hall the talk of The Paradise.
听上去真不错啊 先生
That sounds marvellous, sir.
那么你会给我来点什么?
So what will you provide me with?
您心中想的是什么? 威斯顿先生
What did you have in mind, Mr Weston?
我想的是你会给我来点让人难以抗拒的东西
I had in mind that you would offer me something truly irresistible.
那种能放在橱窗展示的东西 梅尔托
Something to put in the front window, Myrtle.
它的美甚至让珠宝相形见绌
Something that might outshine even a jewel.
我尽力 先生
I will, sir.
让我好好地想一想 看看我能想出点什么来
Let me just scratch my head for a while, see what I can come up with.
当然了 我会很快再和你聊的
Of course. We'll speak again soon.
- 凯瑟琳 - 哦!
- Katherine. - Oh!
事实证明 你父亲的表确实是一块珍宝
Your father's watch has proven to be quite a success.
你说的对 当然了
You were right, of course.
我就知道你是对的
I should have known you would be.
它是一件那么华丽的珍宝
Well, it's such a magnificent treasure,
我现在知道了你独自珍藏的原因了
I can understand why you might want to keep it to yourself.
哦 但是我并不想永远留在手里
Oh, but I did not always wish to keep it.
有些话我难以启齿 你听了也会觉得不可思议
I know it is difficult to say, and to hear, such a thing.
但是似乎于我而言 最好还是将事实告诉你
But it seems to me now it is better to tell the truth.
我们一起经历的了这么多的事情 你和我
We have been through so much together, you and I.
我们之间当然不需要任何的隐藏了
Surely we have no room for pretences any more.
我必须要坦白
I have a confession to make.
我没有把这块怀表给汤姆的原因
Why I have never passed the watch on to Tom.
因为我的父亲想要把它给你
My father wanted you to have it.
真的吗 凯瑟琳?
Is that true, Katherine?
你父亲从来没有对我表现出如此的喜爱
Your father did not exhibit such a fondness for me.
是真的
It is true.
差不多吧
Almost true.
我想让他把表给你 在我们的...
I wanted him to give it to you at our...
我似乎无法让这种念头消散
I can't seem to let that idea go.
也许这就是我无法把表给汤姆的原因吧
Perhaps that is why I can't face giving it to Tom.
过往发生的一切事情 我知道你无法原谅我
I know you can never forgive me for what happened,
因为我那样对你 对你的...
for what I did to you, and to your...
请别糟蹋了我的好意
Don't spoil it, please.
这么想对汤姆不公平
It feels unfair to Tom to feel this way.
这就是为什么我这样下定决心
Which is why I have decided it is best
汤姆永远也不会知道
he never knows that
这块表本是应该传给我的丈夫的
my father intended his watch to go to my husband.
我明白
I understand.
你注意到了吗?
Have you noticed?
我们又像以前一样沿街漫步了
We have fallen into promenading along the street, as we used to.
有些东西永远不会消失
Some things are never lost.
- 威斯顿夫人 - 请坐过来 克莱拉
- Mrs Weston. - Sit with me, Clara.
我正想和你私下里聊一聊
I was hoping to speak with you privately.
你为什么想要和我聊天呢 夫人?
Why would you wish to speak to me, ma'am?
你大概是德妮丝最亲近的朋友了吧
You are perhaps closest to Denise.
我在担忧她会怎么想那块表的事情
I have been concerned how she might be feeling about the watch.
那块表?
The watch?
她对那块表很在意吗? 威斯顿夫人
I don't know that she's greatly aware of it, Mrs Weston.
我想说的是
What I mean is,
我竟然把我家族里这样贵重的物品交付于他
that I should entrust Moray with such a precious thing from my family.
我的理解是 那块表是为了促销 夫人
My understanding is that it was here for a promotion, ma'am.
是的 是的 是这样
Yes. Yes, that is so.
但是这种事很容易被误解
But these things can easily be misinterpreted,
考虑到是莫里这样的人
given the kind of man Moray is,
你我心里都清楚
as both you and I know.
那他是怎样的人?
And what kind of man is that?
一个受情绪所控的人
A man ruled by his passions.
我不想让任何人觉得我给了他鼓励
I would not like anyone to think I had encouraged him.
任何人 你的意思是说德妮丝?
By anyone, you mean Denise?
你为什么不考虑一下德妮丝的感受?
Why would you be concerned for Denise's feelings?
现在 我们对另一个女人的同情
There comes a point when our fellow-feeling for another woman
最能触动我们的心
is what touches us most.
坦率的讲 自从莫里伤害了我们 克莱拉
Frankly, since Moray has hurt both you and me, Clara,
我们的同情心已经没有了 不是吗
our sympathies go, do they not,
对那些现在还爱着他
to the woman who loves him now...
...还信任他的女人的同情心?
..who trusts him now?
夫人 你是在告诉我他...
Ma'am, are you telling me that he has...
你和我一样了解他 克莱拉
You know the kind of man he is as well as I do, Clara.
现在 我要你放松 苏西
Now, I want you to relax, Susy.
放松
Relax.
- 放松 - 或许你只要放慢呼吸
- Relax. - Perhaps if you just breathe gently.
现在...
Now...
我要你看着这块表
I want you to look at the watch.
我要你相信这块表的力量
I want you to believe in the power that is in this watch.
它是你眼中唯一能看到的
It is the only thing that your eyes can see,
它是世上仅有的东西
the only thing in the world.
让你的眼睛跟随着它
Let your eyes follow the watch.
你能感觉到你的眼睛变得很重 很累
You can feel your eyes growing heavy, tired.
你感觉到你想要闭上双眼
You can feel you want to close your eyes.
让你的眼皮放下来 闭上
Let your eyelids fall, closed.
闭上眼睛
Closed.
你依然能看到这块表 苏西
You can still see the watch, Susy,
因为它在你脑海里
because the watch is in your mind.
这感觉很奇妙 是你从未体会过的美妙
It feels wonderful. It is the best you have ever felt.
现在我要你伸出你的双手 苏西
Now I want you to hold out your hands for me, Susy.
我要在你的两手间放一只铅笔
I'm going to put a pencil in between your fingers.
你能感觉到吗?
Can you feel that?
现在这只铅笔夹在你的指尖上
Now the pencil is becoming stuck to your fingertips.
这只表想要你感受铅笔在你的指尖有多么牢固
The watch wants you to feel how stuck the pencil is.
你想让它掉下去但是你做不到
You want to let go of it but you can't
因为它已经粘在你的指尖上 它不会掉的
because it's stuck to your fingertips. It won't drop.
现在我要从你的指尖上拿走铅笔 苏西
Now I'm going to take the pencil from your fingertips, Susy,
因为这只表想要你放开铅笔
because the watch wants you to let it go...
现在!
now!
当我一吹口哨 苏西 你就睁开眼睛 慢慢地
When I whistle a tune, Susy, you will open your eyes, slowly
慢慢地 当你睁开眼睛
slowly, and when you open your eyes
你的脑海中只有一件事
you will have only one thought in your mind.
我一定要请山姆喝杯啤酒
I must buy Sam a beer.
我要请山姆喝杯啤酒
I will buy Sam a beer.
山姆是个好小伙 山姆是个英俊的野兽
Sam is a fine lad. Sam is a handsome beast.
一个女孩会为山姆这样的小伙倾心
A girl could fall for a lad like Sam.
请山姆喝一杯
Buy Sam a beer.
我们今晚要去三冠酒店吗?
Are we going over to the Three Crowns tonight?
我要请山姆喝一杯
I want to buy Sam a beer.
乔纳斯 非常感谢你今晚能来
Jonas, thank you for coming out here at night.
我们喝一杯怎么样?
Shall we have a drink?
我以前从未发现山姆是这么英俊
I never realised how handsome Sam is before.
我真为他着迷
I've quite fallen for him.
我能看出来 乔纳斯 你是一个
I see in you, Jonas, a man
只想为你的雇主专心服务的人
who wishes only to be of service to his employer.
遗憾的是 我们已经有了共识
Sadly, we have established, have we not,
莫里不值得你对他这么忠诚 不是吗?
that Moray is undeserving of your loyalty?
我知道你的感受
I know how you feel.
我和我的妻子诚心诚意地让莫里回到这
My wife and I have in good faith brought Moray back here,
给他一个值得信任并负责任的职位
given him a position of responsibility and trust,
但我仍感觉他在密谋
yet I have the feeling he's plotting
想从我们身边夺走天堂百货
to take The Paradise away from us.
如果他真是这样 先生 他隐藏的可够好的
Well, if he is, sir, he's keeping it well hidden.
关键是 乔纳斯
The point is, Jonas,
我看重并且信任你对商场所付出一切
I value and trust your dedication to the store.
我必须要承认 先生 天堂百货所缺少的
I do have to admit, sir, that what The Paradise sorely needs is
正是像您这样的人
a man, like you,
让这个地方的荣誉能得以恢复
to restore some honour to the place.
一个与众不同的战士 我们怎能不跟随您呢?
A soldier of distinction - how can we not follow you?
想想看我能在一个您这样
To think that I am working for a man
勇于为国家奉献的人手下工作
who served his country so heroically.
你怎么知道我在军队服过役?
How do you know about my time in the army?
请原谅 威斯顿先生
Forgive me, Mr Weston.
军旅生涯一直是我所向往的
Military history is a passion of mine.
印度兵变真是个野蛮的行动
The Indian Mutiny was a barbaric business
对我来说 能坐在一个经历了那战役的人
and for me to find myself sitting next to a man
指挥战斗 因为英勇而授勋的人身边...
who was there, an officer who led the fight, was decorated for his courage...
能为您这样的人服务是我莫大的荣幸 先生
it would be a great honour to serve you in any way you consider, sir.
密切监视莫里
Keep a watch on Moray.
弄清楚他在密谋什么
Find out what he is contriving.
您选的这只真是太棒了 真惹人注目
Ah, it's a wonderful piece you've chosen. Spectacular.
那么 慢走 谢谢
Well, enjoy and thank you.
我们今晚一起出去吗?
Shall we walk out tonight?
或许我们都会去三冠酒店
Aye, we'll probably all go over to The Three Crowns, I suppose.
不 我没说所有人 我是说就你和我
Well, no, I don't mean all. I mean just you and me.
苏西 关于那只表的所有小把戏
Susy, all that carry on with the watch,
都只是开玩笑的
it was just a lark.
你真是个英俊的野兽
You're such a handsome beast.
苏西 催眠术只不过是个笑话
Susy. Hypnosis - it's nothing more than a joke.
那只表也没有任何力量 它只是一只表
That watch has no power. It's just a watch.
- 你用它来看时间而已 - 我爱上你了
- You tell the time with it. - I could fall for a lad like you.
我能说 慢点 你没有爱上我 什么都没发生
Can I just say, slow down? You're not in love with me. Nothing happened.
也许你觉得发生了什么
You might think that something happened
但那只是因为 你就是这样的人
but that's just because, well, it's the kind of person you are.
所以如果你能仔细想想
So if you could just get it into your mind
那只表并没有让你爱上我
that that watch did not make you fall in love with me.
达德利先生来了 你最好赶快回你的部门
Oh, there's Mr Dudley, you'd better get back to your department.
- 晚上见 - 好的
- See you tonight. - Sure.
能否给我来杯茶 梅尔托?
Any chance of a cup of tea, Myrtle?
我今晚真不敢去酒吧了
I daren't go to the pub tonight.
苏西好像把那个该死的催眠当真了
Susy seems to think that that damned hypnotism was real.
她一直对我暗送秋波
She keeps making eyes at me
像个忠实的小狗一样缠着我
and pestering me like a devoted puppy.
山姆 你正是我要的人
Oh, Sam, you're just the lad I need.
威斯顿先生让我为美食厅做点特别的
Mr Weston has asked me to do something special for the Food Hall
但我的脑子里一点概念都没有
and there's not a notion in my head.
我不是厨子 梅尔托
I'm no cook, Myrtle.
不 但你可以用你的表给我催眠
No, but you could mesmerise me with the watch
那么也许我会突发灵感
so that something might appear.
我不是说了吗? 那是胡说八道的
Didn't I just say? It's nonsense.
我都是装的 那只是个笑话 哈哈!
I was pretending. It was a joke. Ha-ha!
是的 我知道 但你能不能试试?
Yes, I know that. But will you try?
你好 山姆
Hello, Sam.
德妮丝 你的演讲真让人大受鼓舞
Denise, your presentation was quite an inspiration.
- 每个人都在谈论你 - 谢谢 先生
- Everyone is talking about it. - Thank you, sir.
我突然想到或许你应该在每个部门都呆一天
Yes. It occurs to me that you might spend a day in each department,
给他们注入从你身上散发出来的那种生活乐趣
infuse them with that joie de vivre that seems to spill out of you.
呃 先生 我们实施政策之前
Er, isn't this something we ought to discuss
不应该先讨论一下吗?
before implementing policy on the hoof, sir?
以我的经验来说 经营一家商场
In my experience of running a store,
这种决策应该先在管理层中讨论过
one must consider such things amongst management
再通知员工
before speaking to the staff.
你怎么想的 德妮丝?
What do you think, Denise?
- 先生 能否... - 不能 德妮丝?
- Sir, if I may... - You may not. Denise?
这不是我能决定的 先生
It is not for me to decide, sir.
我不是在让你决定 我是在问你的意见
I'm not asking you to decide. I'm asking for your opinion.
我可以的 先生 当然要其他部门都同意
It could only work, sir, with the consent of the other departments.
没问题 你可以从厨房开始
Of course. You can start in the kitchens.
我看不出来梅尔托会反对 你呢?
I can't see Myrtle objecting, can you?
只要能找到机会
Every opportunity he can find
他就对德妮丝大加赞扬并四处推广
he is lavishing praise and promotion onto Denise.
莫里 你现在比任何时候都要学会控制
Moray, now more than ever you must show restraint.
他仗势欺人 我们都知道他是个怎样的混蛋
He is a bully. We all know what a bully he is.
一个被宠坏的孩子肯定会自行其事
A spoiled child who must have his own way.
我求你 别把事弄大了 别密谋反对他
I implore you, do not rise to this. Do not scheme against him.
我不会让他弄垮我的
I will not let him crush me.
我知道 你在谋画些什么
You're up to something. I know it.
为什么你不告诉我...?
Why won't you tell me...?
达德利 相信我 我知道我在做什么
Dudley, just trust that I know what I'm doing.
我不能 忠诚不是条单行道
I cannot. Loyalty is not a one-way track.
我试图鼓励你来告诉我到底发生了什么
I have tried to encourage you to tell me what is going on.
你拒绝了 也就是说你不信任我
You refuse. That means you do not trust me.
达德利...
Dudley...
你还把希望都寄托于乔纳斯
Yet you choose to lay your faith in Jonas.
这是为了我们大家都好
It's for the good of all of us.
那为什么我从你脸上看到的不是这样?
Then why is that not what I see in your face?
你来主管? 我的厨房?
In charge? You? My kitchen?
不是主管 不是
Not in charge, no.
就一天而已 也许我们在一起会很开心
Simply, for one day, we might have some fun together.
如果你不愿意我不会这样做的 梅尔托
I don't wish to do this if you don't want me here, Myrtle.
如果一天变成了两天呢 然后呢
What if one day becomes two? What then?
威斯顿先生想要一份橱窗展品
Mr Weston wants a display for the window.
我觉得... 梅尔托蛋糕最好
I thought... Myrtle Cake.
梅尔托蛋糕?
Myrtle Cake?
你的食谱 十八个鸡蛋
Your recipe. Eighteen eggs.
我可以装饰一边的窗户 还有鸡
We could decorate the window at one end, chickens.
活鸡 用玉米喂它们
Live chickens, feeding on corn.
第二层摆上堆积如山的鸡蛋
And next to that a mountain of eggs.
然后 在漂亮的展台上的就是 梅尔托蛋糕
And then, on a beautiful stand - Myrtle Cake.
梅尔托蛋糕
Myrtle Cake.
你可以用各种糖果和装饰来美化它
You could decorate it with all manner of sweets and ornaments.
我们也许可以
We might sell the recipe.
向买蛋糕的顾客售卖食谱
And for those customers who buy the cake,
他们可以来你的厨房
they could come into your kitchen
听你是如何学到做这个蛋糕的故事
and hear your tales of how you learned to make the cake.
你告诉威斯顿先生这个主意了吗?
Did you tell Mr Weston this idea?
- 还没有 - 我们可以一起告诉他
- Not yet. - We might tell him together.
过来 如果你想在我的厨房工作
Here! If you're going to be working in my kitchen
你需要一条围裙
you'll need an apron.
你知道我们要放什么在梅尔托蛋糕里吗?
You know what we might put in this Myrtle Cake?
柠檬 蜜糖和姜来给蛋糕一点梅尔托的味道
Lemon and treacle and ginger to give it that bit of Myrtle spice!
忙着掌控世界啊 德妮丝
So busy taking over the world, Denise,
你应该认真确定你没有错过真正重要的部分
you ought to be careful you don't miss out what really matters.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
你那么喜欢这个 不是吗?
Well, you love it all so much, don't you?
他们可以把你放在店里的任何角落
They could drop you anywhere in the store,
城市的任何地方
anywhere in the city,
然后你让事情按着你的方式来
and you would make it sing to your tune.
- 那又怎么样呢? - 没什么
- What's wrong with that? - Nothing.
确实那样没什么不对的
There is really nothing wrong with that.
你想对我说什么 克莱拉?
What are you trying to say to me, Clara?
朋友们尝试警告我
Friends tried to warn me
我生活的方式会赶上我
the way I lived me life would catch up with me
但是我必须自己领会
but I had to learn it for myself.
也许我们都需要自己领会
Perhaps we all have to learn it for ourselves.
山姆 我听说我父亲的手表曾引起轰动
I hear my father's watch has caused something of a stir, Sam.
夫人 我会说 这比轰动更厉害
More of a splash than a stir, I would say, ma'am.
我想请问你 当你告诉我们这个手表...
Might I ask when you told us about the watch,
那个... 催眠术
you know, the hypnotism
还有你父亲在你小时候给你施法的事情
and your father saying that as a child he could put you under his spell,
那都是开玩笑吗?
that was all jest?
当然啦 我父亲很会说笑
Yes, of course. My father was quite the tease.
正如我所想的
That's what I thought.
他只是骗骗我而已
He was fooling with me, that's all.
但是 有一次他说服了我
Except, there was that one time he convinced me
在手表的影响下我说了外语
that under the influence of the watch I had spoken a foreign language.
我想是希腊语
Greek, I believe.
- 希腊语? - 是啊 但是真的很有趣
- Greek? - Yes, but it was all rather good fun.
确实有一件事让我感到惊讶
There was that one incident that did rather astonish me.
小时候 我不爱吃卷心菜
As a child, I refused to eat cabbage,
但是有一次
yet on one occasion,
我父亲在饭桌上拿手表在我眼前晃
my father dangled the watch in front of me at the dinner table
然后我吃了很多卷心菜 也没有抱怨
and I ate a plateful without complaint.
- 卷心菜? - 我甚至乐在其中
- Cabbage? - I rather enjoyed it, too.
- 我想孩子总是乐于接受建议的 - 是的
- I suppose a child's mind is open to suggestion. - Yes. That's it.
有一个关于做这个手表的人的神秘故事
Oh, and there was such a mystery about the watchmaker who made it.
他左手似乎有六个手指
He had six fingers on his left hand, apparently.
他还能看到未来
And he could see into the future.
我父亲喜欢跟我说这些故事
My father loved to tell me these stories.
那些故事总让我吓坏了
They used to frighten the life out of me.
六个手指
Six fingers.
失陪了 先生
Excuse me a moment, sir.
你肯定会觉得我一直在关注传家宝
You will think I am keeping an eye on the family heirloom,
我来得太勤了
I'm in here so often.
完全没有 很高兴见到你
Not at all. It's a pleasure to see you.
实际上 我想...
In truth, I wanted to...
我想我那天说了太多了
I think I said rather too much the other day.
不不不 我很高兴我们聊天了 凯瑟琳
No, no, no, no. I'm glad that we spoke, Katherine.
我很高兴知道我们之间的感情没有消失
It has eased my mind to know that the fondness between us is not lost.
我也这么觉得
Yes. I feel the same way.
如果像我们之前那样亲密的两个人之间有敌意
When two people have been as close as we were, - then it hurts too much for
- 那就太伤人了 - 是啊
- there to be any ill will. - Yes.
也许我们可以时常聚聚喝杯咖啡
Perhaps we could meet from time to time, for coffee?
- 我很乐意 - 那我们一定要聚聚
- I would like that. - Well, then, we must.
也许... 汤姆有时候会无理地嫉妒
Perhaps... Tom can be so unreasonably jealous sometimes,
所以不要让他知道
it would be unhelpful for him to know.
如果你希望这样 那我当然会尊重你的意愿
If that is what you prefer, then, of course, I will respect your wishes.
莫里 你愿意和我还有我妻子一起共进晚餐吗
Moray! Would you be so kind as to join my wife and I for dinner?
如果你希望的话
If you wish, sir.
我是说 我很高兴你邀请我 我有一点意外
What I mean is, I am grateful for the invitation, if a little surprised.
我有一些消息
I have some news.
好消息最好是伴着香槟酒到来
Good news is always best delivered with a glass of champagne.
对我来说是好消息吗 你让我好奇了
Good news for me? You have me curious, sir.
这好消息是给德妮丝的
The news is for Denise.
是你来邀请她还是我来?
Will you invite her or shall I?
你好 山姆
Hello, Sam.
我得赶回店里
I've just got to run back to the store.
他有消息为什么不直接告诉我们呢?
If he has news, then why doesn't he simply tell us?
为什么邀请我们去他家?
Why invite us to the house?
想到和他们共进晚餐就苦恼
The thought of dinner with them is excruciating.
你自己说的 我们必须和他们保持良好的关系
You said yourself, we must keep good relations with them
这正是我们现在在做的
and that is what we are doing.
- 我不相信他 - 我想他也不相信你
- I don't trust him. - I don't suppose he trusts you either.
你是什么意思呢?
What do you mean?
他知道你想要把天堂百货拿回来
He knows you want The Paradise back
你在千方百计达到你的目的
and that you are looking for ways to do that.
我们必须谨慎 德妮丝
We must be wary, Denise.
不管是什么消息 其中肯定有陷阱
Whatever this news is, there will be a trap in it.
约翰 也许这个晚上是向他们证明
John, perhaps this evening is an opportunity to prove to them
我们很融洽的机会
how devoted we are to one another
我们一起就不用害怕他们
and that together we're not afraid of them.
是的
Yes.
晚餐? 这里? 他们两个人?
Dinner? Here? The two of them?
- 我想一定会很有趣 - 你应该先问问我
- I thought it might be rather fun. - You might have asked me.
也许你和莫里在众目睽睽之下
And you might have asked me before you took to
沿着托尔盖特街散步之前
promenading along Tollgate Street with Moray,
- 也应该先问问我 - 我明白了
- for all the world to gaze upon and wonder. - I see.
我了解到 在那个职位上 她有很强的欲望
I have learnt by being about that place that she has quite an appetite.
德妮丝很有野心 我很乐意去培养她
Denise is bubbling with ambition. It pleases me to foster that.
她所有的表现都比他更出色
She shows every sign of outshining him.
莫里也许不是适合她的男人
Moray may prove to be not man enough for her.
我喜欢在这里招待她这个主意
I like the idea of entertaining her here.
我猜她会喜欢烛光闪闪的晚餐
I suspect she will have a taste for a little glitter.
正如我说的 威斯顿先生在战斗中受伤了
Mr Weston, as I suggested to you, sir, was injured in battle.
"退役军官因战斗英勇获维多利亚十字勋章"
恐怕伤得很严重
Hurt badly it would seem.
从印度回来 从军队退役
Returned home from India, retired from the army.
那是否就可以解释...?
Then might that not explain...?
汤姆・威斯顿为他的国家效力
Tom Weston was serving his country
我却在这里卖最新的时尚品
while I was here selling the latest fashions.
难怪他对我这样的人有怨恨
Is it any wonder he holds a grudge against men like me?
他已经遭受了远超我想象的痛苦
Is it not shameful of us to inflict further turmoil
我们还对要对付他 不是很可耻吗?
on the soldier who's suffered beyond anything I can imagine?
如果你可怜他 你就永远不能打败他
If you pity the man you will never defeat him.
先生 恕我直言
Sir, if I may.
威斯顿先生必须知道那只手表的事
Mr Weston must learn about the watch, sir.
我能找到机会告诉他
I can find an opportunity to present him with the knowledge
他的妻子向他隐瞒了她父亲的意愿
that his wife has concealed from him her father's intentions.
不 乔纳斯 别在我读了这个之后这么做
No, Jonas. Not after reading this.
我不想他知道
I don't want him to know.
我告诉你 艾德蒙 我没有把它放进口袋
I tell you, Edmund. I didn't put it in my pocket.
但是你一定把它放在那儿了 你只是忘记了
But you must have put it there. You've forgotten.
这就更糟糕了
That's worse, isn't it?
我把它放进自己的口袋却都不知道
I put it in my own pocket and I didn't even realise I was doing it?
就好像手表自己走到那里的一样
It's like the watch put itself there.
- 山姆 这对话太疯狂了 - 那手表
- Sam, lad, this is wild talk. - That thing.
对了 有个在海湾工作的家伙
Right, there's this fella who works in the bay
李 雷蒙德・李 李跳蚤
Lee, Raymond Lee. Lee the Flea.
我从来都不喜欢那个家伙
I never liked the bloke
他昨天一直对我喋喋不休
and he was rattling on me yesterday, on and on.
我站在我的柜台 我脑子里在想咒语
I'm standing at my counter, I'm cursing in my head.
今天 你猜怎么着 他生病在床上了
Now today, what do you think? He's taken sick to his bed.
怎么会这样?
How does that happen?
那是因为有时候人们会生病
It happens because sometimes people get ill.
不不
No, no.
是那手表 我知道的
It's the watch. I know it is.
苏西像狗皮膏药一样一直绕着我转
I've got Susy following me around like a sop.
我怎么也甩不掉她
I can't shake her out of it no matter what I do.
如果这让你那么烦恼
Well, if it's bothering you that much,
你为什么不叫达德利先生把你调离手表柜台呢
why don't you ask Mr Dudley to take you off the watch counter?
我会的
I will. I will.
就... 就这么办
That's... That's what I'll do.
太值得称赞了 对吧莫里
It is so laudable, is it not, Moray,
一个女孩从一个小镇来
for a girl to come from a lowly little town like...
- 是哪里 德妮丝 - 先生 是皮布尔斯
- Where is it, Denise? - Peebles, sir.
皮布尔斯 甚至连名字读起来都是一种款待
Peebles. Even the word is a treat on the tongue.
我和凯瑟琳都难以想象 从小城镇到大城市
Katherine and I have no idea what it means to come from such beginnings
并在大城市证明自己 意味着什么
and to prove oneself in the city.
我想这不亚于
I suppose it's no small feat
想在军队里证明自己 威斯顿先生
to prove oneself in the armed forces, Mr Weston.
是啊 很恰当的比喻
Yes. There is that.
但对于一个女人
But for a woman,
一个年轻的女人在男人的世界
a young woman in a man's world,
打拼 满怀着...
and to do it all with such...
那叫什么 莫里?
What shall we call it, Moray?
- 渴望? - 哦 不!
- Eagerness? - Oh, come!
这不是我所想的 我想说满怀着这样的热情
That is not what I meant at all. I mean with such effervescence.
我们想知道是什么消息 先生
We were wondering what the news might be, sir.
他庆幸过自己的幸运吗 德妮丝?
Does he appreciate what a fortunate man he is, Denise?
我希望他庆幸过
I hope he does.
他有过 而且我也很庆幸能跟约翰一起工作
Yes. And I am very fortunate to work with John.
他经常鼓励我
He's always encouraged me.
是吗 莫里?
Do you, Moray?
知道你身边的女人有多优秀吗?
Do you realise quite what a woman you have on your hands?
不知道我就是傻瓜了 先生
I'd be a fool not to, sir.
我是有消息
News indeed.
我们想送你去巴黎 德妮丝
We want to send you to Paris, Denise.
这是一个考察任务
On a reconnaissance mission.
你去探访乐蓬马歇百货
To visit Le Bon Marche
了解最新的法国时尚
and to fill your eyes with the latest French fashions.
是吗! 这真是太...
Well! That is rather...
我不知道该说什么
I don't quite know what to say.
谢谢!
Thank you!
一周的时间 你就尽情享受巴黎的时尚吧
Spend a week there. Immerse yourself in all things Parisienne.
我希望我们女装部的主管能深入了解插画时尚
We want our Head of Ladieswear to be versed in La Mode Illustree.
插画时尚: 法国第一本主要的时尚杂志
你觉得自己可以出行吗?
Do you think you are ready for such a trip?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
德妮丝在巴黎!
Denise in Paris!
你知道他对我们做了什么吗? 亲爱的
'Don't you see what he is doing to us, darling?'
他在给你奖赏 你却欣然接受了
He's feeding you with prizes so that you feel happy here,
你遵照了他的想法
so that you accept the way things are.
去巴黎我能学到很多
I could learn so much in Paris.
我不是想阻止你
It's not that I want to stop you from going.
只是想让你意识到他干了什么
I want you to see what he's doing.
我会想办法拒绝他
I'll find a reason to say no.
跟他说我生病了 或是这次出行会让我生病
I'll tell him I'm sick or that the travelling will make me ill.
这都是为了我们好 德妮丝
It is for us that I am doing this, Denise,
为了我们能一起在天堂百货
so we can be together in The Paradise.
我明白
I know.
我一直想做台前的工作
I always wanted it to be me out front
但现在我的点心替我受到关注
but it feels better for it to be my baking
让我更开心
what's in the limelight.
谢谢你 德妮丝
Thank you, Denise.
"梅尔托蛋糕"
达德利先生 请您批准 先生
Mr Dudley, sir, with your permission, sir,
我想调离怀表柜台
I would like to be taken off the watch counter.
但怀表是我们的畅销品之一
But the watches are our best-selling item.
你在创造奇迹
You're working wonders.
但是 如果您能批准 先生
But still, if you will, sir.
我会很感激
I'd appreciate the move.
你从没赚过那么多奖金 为什么不做呢
You've never earned so much bonus. Why would you turn your back on that?
卖怀表不适合我 我宁愿回去卖丝绸
Watches aren't for me. I prefer to go back to silks.
我会考虑看看
I'll give it some thought.
您能现在就考虑吗? 您就站在这儿
Could you give it some thought now, sir, while you're standing here?
如果职员都随意调来调去 会影响不好
It creates a bad impression if staff are hopping about from counter to counter.
我希望你能继续工作
I want you to see it through with the watches.
- 要是我恳求您呢? 先生 - 为什么?
- If I were to plead with you sir? - But for what reason?
给我个合理的理由 我会考虑看看
Give me a sound reason and I will give it some consideration.
那好吧 达德利先生
Very well, Mr Dudley, sir.
进来
Come in.
我要你告诉他
I want you to tell him.
告诉汤姆・威斯顿
Tell Tom Weston that
格伦德宁勋爵打算把自己的怀表
Lord Glendenning intended his watch
传给凯瑟琳的丈夫 但她隐瞒了他
to be left to Katherine's husband but she's kept this from him.
你还在卖那些表吗?
You're still doing the watches then?
我请求达德利先生将我们调走 但他拒绝了
I asked Mr Dudley to move us but he refused.
看那表 挂在那儿像是在嘲笑我们
Look at it. Hangs there like it's mocking us.
山姆 你得冷静 你要失去理智了
Sam, you need to calm down. You're letting your mind run away with you.
那玩意儿还在那儿 你让我怎么冷静?
How can I calm down when the thing's right there?
它要禁锢我们 我恨它
It wants to possess us. - I hate it.
山姆 别说了!
Sam, stop it!
我有种冲动 想把它扔进河里
I'm getting such urges in my mind, hat I want to throw it in the river,
走上桥 放进包里 外加一颗石头
go down to the bridge, put it in a bag with a stone
然后扔进水里 摆脱它
and toss it into the water, be rid of it.
然后我可能会恢复平静
Then I might be at peace again.
山姆 一旦你这么做 你将在监狱度过余生
Sam, if you do that you'll end up in prison.
这是块贵重的表 凯瑟琳・威斯顿的表
This is a valuable watch. It's Katherine Weston's watch.
我也不想那么做 但我没法不去想
I don't want to do it. But I can't stop thinking it.
好吧 也许它很快会物归原主 嗯?
Well, perhaps it'll go back where it came from soon, eh?
要跟我喝一杯吗 乔纳斯?
Will you join me in a drink, Jonas?
我... 我得工作了 先生
I... I should be getting on with my duties, sir.
我是你老板 你现在的工作就是和我喝一杯
I'm your employer. Your duty at this moment is to enjoy a drink with me.
你怎么回事?
What's the matter with you?
难道你发现莫里在玩什么鬼把戏了?
Did you find out what Moray is up to?
我没有关于莫里财政的情报 先生
I have no intelligence on Mr Moray's finances, sir.
谨慎说话 乔纳斯
You chose your words too carefully, Jonas.
你在隐瞒我什么?
What are you concealing from me?
你有事 我能看出来
You have something on your mind. I can see it.
这我不能说 先生
It is not for me to tell a man such things, sir.
什么事?
What things?
这很危险 当一个男人意识到...
It is dangerous when a husband learns...
我妻子?
My wife?
到底是什么 告诉我你所知道的
What is it? I insist you tell me what you know.
- 先生 请别问 - 告诉我
- Please, sir! - Tell me.
那块怀表 先生
The watch, sir.
我看见您的妻子跟莫里在交谈
I saw your wife talking to Mr Moray.
怀表怎么了?
What about the watch?
她父亲遗留给她那块表是要传给她的丈夫
Her father bequeathed that the piece was to be passed on to the man she married.
您明白了吧 先生 为什么我不能说
Now you see, sir, why this is impossible for me to tell.
说下去
Carry on.
她决定不告诉你她父亲的遗愿
She has decided not to tell you of her father's wishes.
你听见她跟莫里说这个?
You heard her telling Moray this?
她要求他保密 就他们两人知道
She asked him to keep it a secret, between them.
我明白了
I see.
威斯顿先生 我恐怕不能接受您的好意
Mr Weston, I'm afraid I can't accept your kind of offer
去巴黎的事
of a trip to Paris.
我发誓 先生 锁柜台的时候还在的
I promise you, gentlemen. When I closed up my counter it was there.
- 但现在不在了 山姆 - 不是 先生
- But it is not there now, Sam. - No, sir.
我检查过口袋也不在
I've checked my pockets and it's not there.
为什么你会想到检查口袋?
Why would you want to check your pockets?
我 我是说 没错... 很奇怪的 先生
What, what I mean is, right the... The thing is strange, sir.
有天晚上 我知道这难以置信
One night - and I know this is going to be difficult to believe -
我把表收好后 回到房间
I put it away and I went to my room
结果表在我的...
and it was, it was in my...
先生 我从没想过拥有那块表
Gentlemen, I have no wish to want that watch.
那该死的表真的着魔了
That damned watch is bewitched.
威斯顿先生拿走了那块表 我看见他拿走了
Mr Weston took the watch. I saw him take it.
所以它走了
Then it's gone.
我又恢复自由了!
I'm a free man again!
我该怎样阻止她老跟着我
How do I stop her following me all the time
注视我犹如我是爱神丘比特?
and looking at me like I'm the God of Love?
还有一见到我就说 "你好 山姆 "?
And saying, "Hello, Sam," every time I see her?
你再给她催眠一次
You'll have to hypnotise her again.
我一开始就没给她催眠过
I didn't hypnotise her in the first place.
而且表也还回去了
And the watch is gone now.
就算你告诉苏西你会用鸡毛掸子给她催眠
Susy would believe it if you told her you'd hypnotised her
她也会相信
with a feather duster.
让我来吧
Leave it to me.
在你睁开眼睛后
When you wake up
你会觉得山姆只是个普通的小伙子
you will think that Sam is just a lad,
跟其他人一样 常常聊天
like all the other lads, plenty of chat,
但你绝对不会嫁给他
but you could never marry him.
我有种奇怪的感觉
I had the strangest feeling.
我...
I...
感觉自己爱上了山姆
I thought I was in love with Sam.
是不是很愚蠢?
Isn't that silly?
要我们转告他你没有吗?
Do we have to tell him that you're not?
我的表又慢了 山姆
It's gone lazy on me again, Sam.
我建议 先生...
May I suggest, sir...
- 修理一下 - 你好 山姆
- Get it fixed. - Hello, Sam.
美食厅取得了巨大的成功
The Food Hall has been a great success.
从来没想过我可能会关心
I had not imagined I might be so engaged by
蛋糕和果子面包怎么能卖得好
by how cakes and buns might sell.
你想今天去参观美食厅吗 芙罗拉?
Would you care to visit the Food Hall today, Flora?
好啊 爸爸
Yes, Papa.
想哪时候去?
What time shall we go?
今天上午晚点可以吗?
Perhaps later this morning?
好啊
Yes.
巴黎
时尚之都
我发现她坐在我的椅子上 似乎想掌权
I found her sitting in my chair as though she were trying out the throne.
'我再也忍受不了!'
'I cannot bear one more day!'
汤姆会毁了你
Tom will destroy you.
德妮丝也会毁了你
Denise will destroy you.
你认为我们应该对抗莫里?
You think we should defy Moray?
应该说是帮助
Let's call it helping.
不让他知道的帮助
Without his knowledge or consent.
我认为秘密行动不是最好的方式 德妮丝
'I'm not sure that acting secretly is the best way, Denise.'